Gary M Davis

PRODUCT & USER EXPERIENCE DESIGNER

gary.davis@gmail.com +1 585 301 0467

PORTFOLIO: https://usersimple.com

Summary

I am a collaborative Principal Designer with a strong background in human-centered problem-solving and design. I have a proven track record of transforming complex B2B, SaaS experiences to drive measurable improvements in usability, user engagement, and customer satisfaction.

Experience

INDEPENDENT Principal Consultant
Webster, NY July 2023 - Present

Provided technology consulting services to clients across domains such as software user experience, industrial design, and artificial intelligence/machine learning. Leveraged expertise in user-centric design, rapid prototyping, and emerging technologies to deliver innovative, value-driven solutions under tight deadlines.

- Contracted with a cloud software startup to enhance existing product capabilities through design thinking and reconceptualization of requirements, inventing novel user experiences beyond initial project scope.
- Broadened industrial design skill set through immersion in 3D CAD/CAM software for an entrepreneurial furniture design and manufacturing venture.
- Pursued comprehensive self-guided learning to deepen AI/ML proficiencies, experimenting with LLMs, generative AI, custom AI assistants, no-code development, and audio transcription.

COUPA

Principal User Experience Designer

San Mateo, CA / Remote

MAR 2022 - JUN 2023

Business Spend Management Platform – Led UX design initiatives reimagining the supplier experience. Collaborated with cross-functional design, product and engineering teams through user-centered design, research, prototyping, and visual asset creation.

- Spearheaded the UX design strategy for a supplier business spend management platform,
 which played an instrumental role in enabling \$43 billion in value for diverse suppliers.
- Redesigned the B2B supplier onboarding workflow, increasing profile completion rates by 40%.
 Also incorporated promotions for a verified program to drive additional revenue through an enhanced onboarding experience.

CLOUDCHECKR/NETAPP

Rochester, NY

Lead User Experience Designer

SEP 2019 - MAR 2022

Cloud Management Platform – Directed UX strategy and design system for B2B cloud management platform. Mentored a junior designer while conducting user research and testing. Partnered with agile product and engineering teams to enhance navigation and workflows.

- Devised a UX strategy with a phased implementation for CloudCheckr's B2B cloud FinOps platform. This strategic initiative yielded tangible improvements across customer value, productivity, and loyalty.
- Designed a UI for onboarding widely divergent authentication types among cloud providers.
 The design resulted in an expansion of our customer base.
- Simplified the complex problem of applying pricing plans across multiple services, customers and rule-sets. This allowed customers to easily and flexibly generate increased revenue.

EAGLEVIEW

Senior User Experience Designer

Rochester, NY

JUL 2018 - SEP 2019

Geomatics and GIS – Drove end-to-end experience design via user research, internal workflow optimization, and intuitive visual solutions. Collaborated across agile product teams to modernize customer-facing services.

 Developed a high-impact design to replace a highly complex image review workflow, resulting in more than 50% increases in productivity and revenue. This strategic redesign significantly improved operational efficiency and financial outcomes.

KODAK ALARIS

User Experience Design Consultant

Rochester, NY

MAR 2015 - OCT 2017

Document Processing Systems – Spearheaded UX enhancements for document processing systems. Managed stakeholders and external vendors to simplify workflows and address usability issues.

- Reduced customer support costs by more than 15% by simplifying highly complex B2B document processing tasks into understandable workflows.
- Established a design system and behavioral strategy that drove a professional, consistent look and feel across embedded, SaaS, desktop, and mobile UX design.

DELL/KACE

Principal User Experience Designer

Mountain View, CA / Remote

MAY 2011 - MAR 2015

Device Management Platforms – Led design efforts as Principal Designer across web, mobile, and emerging platforms. Partnered with agile product teams to envision future-forward solutions.

- Led the design of the new K3000 mobile device management from initial concept to product launch in about one year resulting in sales 50% over the forecast.
- Led the clean-sheet design of the K1000 Go mobile app with a seamless experience across web and mobile platforms. Adopted by one-third of customers in less than 6 months.

EASTMAN KODAK

Senior User Experience Designer

Rochester, NY

JUL 2007 - DEC 2010

Retail Photographic Systems – Modernized legacy UI/UX through generative research, information architecture, and human-centered visual design. Conducted usability studies to iteratively refine and optimize.

- Led a strategic redesign of the flagship Picture-Maker Kiosk UI, which increased the perception of quality by more than 20%, vastly simplified workflow, and reduced clutter.
- Uncovered safety and usability issues through human-factors assessments. Recommended changes eliminated the risk of injury and reduced key support costs by more than 25%.

XEROX

Senior User Experience Designer

Rochester, NY

MAR 1996 - DEC 2006

Led and participated in interdisciplinary teams to design major features and services. Provided User Interaction Design support including competitive benchmarking, workflow analysis, architecture, graphics and nomenclature, usability study planning and reporting, wireframes, storyboards, style guides and detailed specifications.

- Designed print drivers that improved success rates of key tasks by over 200% and were adopted as the company-wide design standard.
- Increased reseller interest in equipment over competitors by devising a complete end-to-end system to direct sales of supplies to the original reseller.
- Enhanced usability and customer satisfaction by unifying several divergent authentication, accounting and access schemes into a single coherent design.
- Increased the collection of revenue by over \$1M per year through redesign of the billing meters UI and establishment of coherent nomenclature across devices.

Skills

- Full-stack skills including user research, usability testing, concept, prototyping, visual, and front-end development
- Expertise using Figma, Balsamiq, Invision, Photoshop, Illustrator, and many others
- Direct experience coding with HTML, CSS, PHP, Bootstrap, JavaScript, and jQuery
- Experienced with both Lean and Agile methods and tools such as Jira and Confluence

Additional Experience

CURRICULUM DESIGN

Rochester Institute of Technology / NTID -Mobile User Interface Design 150

GRAPHIC DESIGN

Marietta – designed labeling and packaging for hotel chain amenities.

Cleary Graphics, Inc. – Created publications and devised software work-group procedures.

INDUSTRIAL DESIGN

Smith Corona – Developed new product concepts and user interface designs.

Crosman Air Guns/ Ranging – Designed new products and assisted the company's expansion into new markets.

Patents

US8046264 - Directing post-sale supplies revenue to original dealer

US7280241 - Print driver user interface

US6134019 – Help button service for a user interface in a digital printing scanning or facsimile system

US7154628 - Job secure overwrite failure notification

Education

SYRACUSE UNIVERSITY - Bachelor of Industrial Design

Portfolio

https://usersimple.com